Guide to the Colonial Africa: Postcard Collection, 1880-1980
Department of Special Collections
- Series 9. Dijbouti
  - Djiboutin.d., 5 postcards (Box 1, Folder 34)
    5 postcards from Djibouti: Place Menelik, the Hospital, La Rue d'Abyssinie, Post office, Somali children
    "Au Cafe de la Paix", Djibouti, Editeur "Au Bon Marche", Djibouti, J-G. Mody, photographe; Djibouti; Hospitals; Street scenes; Post offices; Indigenous people
- Series 10. Egypt
  - Subseries 1. Cities
    - Subsubseries 1. Alexandria
      - Alexandrian.d. (1900-1945), 14 postcards (Box 2, Folder 1)
        This folder contains 14 postcards of Alexandria. Street scenes include Boulevard d'Allemagne, Rue de la Poste. Images of the sea and canals include the Metropole Hotel, Glymenopoulo Beach, and 2 postcards of the Canal Mahmoudieh. Images also include the Moustapha Pacha Barracks, the Nabi Daniel Mosque, the Public Abbatoirs, the Public Gardens, Pompey's Pillar. Images from Ramleh include the Ramleh train station and a scene of Europeans riding horses in front of palm trees.
        Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo; Spiras N. Grivas, Editeur, Alexandria; LL Lehnert and Lardrock, Cairo; Lichtenstern & Harari, Cairo; S.N. Theodossiou, Alexandria; Alexandria, Egypt; Archaeological sites; Barracks; Beaches; Canals; Gardens; Mosques; Panoramic Views; Railroad stations; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 2. Cairo, Pyramids
      - Cairo and pyramids at Gizan.d. (1900-1965), 27 postcards (Box 2, Folder 2)
        This folder contains postcards with images of Cairo and of the Giza pyramids. Includes the following images from Cairo streets: panoramic views, the inside of a house, the university, and the Grand Cafe Chicha. 12 postcards of mosques, the Citadel, and tombs: Mohamed Ali mosque, Kait Bey mosque, Sultan Hassan mosque, Alabaster mosque, tombs of Mamelouks, tombs of caliphs. 9 postcards of pyramids at Giza: Sphinx with camel driver in foreground, Great Pyramid of Chefren, Kafr-el-Haram, views at sunset. 2 postcards of bedouin camps.
        Cairo Postcard Trust; Au Cartosport Max H. Rudmann, Cairo; Castro Brothers Editors, Cairo; Comptoir Philatelique d'Egypte, Alexandria; Ephtimios Freres, Port Said; L. & H., Cairo; LL Lehnert & Landrock, Cairo; Lichtenstern & Harari, Cario; Ocean Comfort Company; University of Cairo; Cairo, Egypt; Forts and fortifications; Indigenous peoples; Mosques; Panoramic views; Pyramids, Egypt; Sphinxes, Egypt; Street scenes; Tombs & sepulchral monuments; Universities
    - Subsubseries 3. Heliopolis
      - Heliopolisn.d., 4 postcards (Box 2, Folder 3)
        4 postcards of Heliopolis, including 2 of the Palace Hotel, and 2 street scenes of the Boulevard Abbas.
        B. Lividas & Coutsicos, Cairo; Heliopolis, Egypt; Hotels; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 4. Nile and Cities on the Nile
      - Nile and cities of Aswan, Karnak, Luxor, Memphis, 11 postcards (Box 2, Folder 4)
        11 postcards of the Nile River and of the cities along the Nile.Includes boats on Nile. Aswan: the Savoy Hotel. the Ferry, Granite quarries. Bedrechin: palm grove Karnak: Avenue of Sphinxes, Pylon of Eugerte. Luxor: Temple and Statue of Ramses, Pigeon Tower of Goornah, Memphis: Alabaster sphinx
        LL Lehnert & Landrock, Cairo; Lichtenstern & Harari, Cairo; Shurey's Publications; Archeaological sites; Aswan, Egypt; Bedrechin, Egypt; Karnak, Egypt; Luxor, Egypt; Memphis, Egypt; Nile River; Sphinxes, Egypt
    - Subsubseries 5. Port Said
      - Port Said Views and Harborn.d., 21 postcards (Box 2, Folder 5)
        The 21 postcards in this folder contain the following: Views of Port Said, the statue of De Lessepsin Lesseps Square, views of the harbor and port, the Quai Francois Joseph and the Agence des Messageries Maritimes, the lighthouse, the entry to the canal. the Suez Canal office, the Casino, street scenes.
        A. K. Mayorkino, Port Said; Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo; Coustoulides, Alexandria; D.J.L. Ephtimios Freres, Port Said; L.C. LLLevy & Neurdein Reunis, Paris; Lichtenstern & Harari; M.S Bazar; Messageries Maritimes; P.C.M.J., Alexandria; Stylianos Coutsicos, Cairo; Canals; Fishing; Harbors; Monuments; Panoramic Views; Port Said, Egypt; Street scenes
      - Port Said, postcards published by the Oriental Commercial Bureaun.d., 11 postcards (Box 2, Folder 6)
        These postcards represent an incomplete numbered set of images of Port Said published by the Oriental Commercial Bureau, Port Said, Egypt. Images include: De Lesseps Statue, the Harbor, the beach, the lighthouse, quai Sultan Hussein, the Canal Company's offices, Prince Farouk Street, Boulevard Fouad I, Avenue Eugenie, view of Arab quarter.
        Oriental Commercial Bureau; Beaches; Canals; Harbors; Monuments; Port Said, Egypt; Street scenes
      - Port Said, postcards published by Lehnert & Landrockn.d., 16 postcards (Box 2, Folder 7)
        An incomplete set of 10 numbered colored postcards of Port Said. Images include: De Lesseps Statue, the Harbor, the Suez Canal, the Casino, Boulevard Fouad I, the Abbes Mosque, the Arab quarter, the beach (the 'Strand'). 6 b & w postcards also published by Lehnert & Landrock. Images include: the port, the lighthouse, De Lesseps Statue, offices of the Suez Canal Company, Prince Farouk Street, the Suez Canal.
        Lehnert & Landrock; Beaches; Canals; Harbors; Monuments; Mosques; Panoramic views; Port Said, Egypt; Street scenes
      - Port Said, postcards published by Isaac Behar, Port Saidn.d., 12 postcards (Box 2, Folder 8)
        12 numbered color postcards of Port Said published by Isaac Behar. Images include: De Lesseps Statue, the Harbor, the Suez Canal, the Palais des Hollandais, the offices of the Suez Canal Company, boats in the canal, the beach, the English Church and convent of Bon-Pasteur, the Marina and lighthouse.
        Isaac Behar, Port Said; Beaches; Canals; Harbors; Monuments; Mosques; Panoramic views; Port Said, Egypt; Religious buildings; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 6. Suez Canal
      - Suez Canal and cities on the Canal except Port Saidn.d., 15 postcards (Box 2, Folder 9)
        This folder contains postcards of the Suez Canal itself and of cities on the canal. Ismailia: floodgate, Lake Timsah, El-Kantara: crossing of the Suez Canal, Suez: views of city, Colmar Street, Port Tewfik: views of port, end of Suez Canal, mosque
        Arougheti Bros., Suez, Cairo Postcard Trust; Edition Egyptienne; Ephtimios Freres, Port Said; Lehnert & Landrock, Cairo; Stylianos Coutsicos, Cairo; Canals; Fishing; Harbors; Ismailia, Egypt; Kantara, Egypt; Mosques; Panoramic views; Street scenes
  - Subseries 2. Various
    - Egypt, variousn.d., 5 postcards (Box 2, Folder 10)
      5 diverse postcards from Egypt: Tomb of Ali at Nedjef, Picture of hieroglyphics: Thebes, thrashing corn, Leaving Damietta 2 postcards of the Isle of Philae
      Droguerie E. Del Mar, Cairo, Port Said; Lehnert & Landrock, Cairo; Shurey's Publications; Egypt; Tombs & Sepulchral monuments
- Series 11. Ethiopia
  - Ethiopian.d., 2 postcards (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Two black and white postcards from Ethiopia/Abyssinia: Addis-Abbaba, Guiorguis Church, Malka-Idda Rapids
    Editions A.M., Addis-Abbaba; Maison A. Benoiston & Cie. Verascope Richard; Churches; Ethiopia, Description and travel; Rivers
  - Gabonn.d., 3 postcards (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Three postcards of Gabon. Two are of the beach at Libreville. One shows an old blind man with a child guiding him.
    Collection C.O.A.; Collection S.H.O.; Societe des Missions Evangeliques, Paris; Beaches; Gabon, Description and travel; Indigenous peoples
- Series 12. Gabon
  - Gabonn.d., 3 postcards (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series 13. German East Africa
  - German East African.d., 8 postcards (Box 2, Folder 13)
    8 postcards from German East Africa. Views include the following: 3 postcards of Mariannhill showing indigenous dwellings. 1 postcard with a color photograph of the church in Moschi, German East Africa. 2 scenes of villages in Tanga. 2 sketches of the tropics.
    Verlag der Missionbuschhandlung, Herrnhut; Verlag des Evang.-luth, Mission zu Leipzig; Beaches; Churches; German East Africa, Description and travel; Villages
- Series 14. Guinea
  - Guinean.d., 13 postcards (Box 2, Folder 14)
    13 postcards from Guinea, West Africa. Includes 11 postcards with images from the city of Conakry: The "Ballay" Monument, the entrance to the city, the Boulevard Circulaire and the Cie. Commerciale d'Exportation, the Chateau d'Eau, the Mission Charles Morel, the celebration of Ramadan, and three identitcal postcards showing the waterfront with the phrase "Visitez l'Afrique occidentale francaise a l'Exposition coloniale de Paris, 1931." 1 postcard of a street in Kankan. One postcard showing the Minister of the Colonies on a voyage at the Tabili railroad station.
    Collection Generale Fortier, Dakar; Edition H.G.F.; Photo A. de Schacht; Photo E. Habkouk; Colonial architecture; Colonial power; Guinea, Description and travel; Islam; Missions; Monuments; Street scenes
- Series 15. Lesotho
  - Lesothon.d., 5 postcards (Box 2, Folder 15)
    5 postcards of Lesotho (Lessouto). Indigenous houses in a cave at Qalo, schoolteacher's family, the mission school at Thabana-Morena, a chief's wife at Thaba-Bosiu.
    Societe des Missions Evangeliques, Paris; Churches; Indigenous peoples; Lesotho; Villages
- Series 16. Libya
  - Libya, Tripolin.d., 9 postcards (Box 2, Folder 16)
    9 postcards of Tripoli, Libya. Scenes include panoramic views of the city taken from the water, the Governor's Palace, rue Azizie, the military barracks, street and market scenes, and il Castello.
    Aula e Bragoni, Tripoli; C. Chierichetti, Milano; Edizione Pirotta & Bresciano, Tripoli; Istituto Italiano per l'Africa, Roma; Architecture, colonial; Colonial power; Harbors; Libya; Markets; Street scenes; Tripoli
- Series 17. Madagascar
  - Subseries 1. Tanarive, Diego Suarez
    - Tananarive, Diego-Suarez, other townsn.d., 15 postcards (Box 2, Folder 17)
      15 postcards of cities and towns in Madagascar. Tananarive: Antaninarena - Ambatonakanga; Analakey - Avenue Falliere and the train station; Governor General Residence and Park; Queen's Palace; Garden of the Prime Minister's Tomb; Andohalo Cathedral; Indigenous Hospital of Befelantanana; Temple of Ambochipotay. Diego-Suarez: Cap Diego; Administrator's Residence; Roussette Waterfall. Other cities: Covered market; Nossi-be - indigenous theater; Majunga - autos
      Couadou, phot., Toulon-sur-Mer, Editeurs Grand Bazar, Charifou Jeewa, Edition Cassam-Chenai, Diego-Suarez, Etablissements Rene Depui, Edit., Imprimerie E. Bachel, Tamatave, Photo Goulamhoussen Charifou fils, Diego-Suarez; Architecture, colonial; Hospitals; Madagascar, Description and travel; Markets; Panoramic views; Waterfalls
  - Subseries 2. Water scenes, people
    - Water scenes, peoplen.d., 11 postcards (Box 2, Folder 18)
      11 postcards of Madagascar. 3 postcards of scenes of boats, the sea, and rivers. 8 postcards with images of people: women water carriers, rice workers, schoolchildren bathing, meal at a school, and nurses and the school at the leper colony at Manankavaly.
      Cliche Maria; Editeurs Grand Bazar, Charifou Jeewa; G. Charifous, edit.; Societe des Missions Evangeliques, Paris; Boats; Children; Indigenous peoples; Leprosy; Madagascar, Description and travel; Rivers; Water carriers
- Series 18. Morocco
  - Subseries 1. Cities
    - Subsubseries 1. Casablanca
      - Casablancan.d., 14 postcards (Box 2, Folder 19)
        Fourteen postcards of Casablanca, Morocco. Images include the following: Banque d'Etat au Maroc; Barracks of the 1er Zoaves; Stock Exchange; Prefecture and Palais de Justice; Parc Lyautey; Marketplace; Arcades of the Nouvelle Kassaria; Slaughterhouse; Place de France; Porte de Marrakech; Rue de l'Horloge; cargo ship Volubilis in harbor; harbor scenes.
        Bertou, Alhambra; CAP; Edit. Kricorian, Casablanca; P. Grebert, Casablanca; Photo Flandrin; Architecture, colonial; Banks; Barracks; Gardens; Harbors; Morocco, Description and travel; Panoramic views; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 2. Tangiers
      - Tangiersn.d., 13 postcards (Box 2, Folder 20)
        Thirteen postcards of Tangiers, Morocco. Images include the following: Panoramic views and street scenes of Tangiers; Cabo Espartel; the beach; Sidi-Bou-Aabaid Mosque; Mosque of the Aissaouas; Casbah; Legation de France; Place de France and Boulevard Pasteur; Boulevard de la Plage and Hotel Cecil; the Charf.
        A. Arevalo, Libreria Espanola y Extrajera, Tangiers; Au Bon Mathurin, Tangiers; Edition Hell, Tangiers; Edition Lebrun; L.L. Phot. Combier, Macon; Beaches; Casbah; Colonial cities; Panoramic views; Morocco, Description and travel; Mosques; Street scenes
    - Subsubseries 3. Cities Except Casablanca and Tangiers
      - Fez; Itzer; Marrakech; Mazagan; Oudjda; Rabat;Safi; Tetuann.d., 17 postcards (Box 2, Folder 21)
        17 postcards of several towns and cities in Morocco. Fez: Panoramic view; indigenous brick oven; Nidjaraine visit; Arab story tellers; Marabout Si-Ahmed-Tijani. Itzer: Main Entrance to city, Marrakech: La Menara; Gueliz Fort; Avenue de la Koutoubia, Mazagan: Portuguese monument; Interior of Camp Requiston, Oudjda: Casbah guarded by Spahis; panoramic view, Rabat: Ruins of the Chellah; Ouidaia and old ramparts; Safi: Bab Chabah; Tetuan: Fortifications
        CAPA. Pleux et Truchi, edit., Fez; Agenda P.L.M.; Edition J. Bousira, Fez; Edition "Lyon Consortium," Casablanca; Editions Jeff, Casablanca; Felix, Photo-edituer, Marrakech; J. Geiser, Algiers; Levy & Neurdem Reunis, Paris; Nahon & Lasry, Tangiers; Photo Flandrin; Schmitt Photo, Rabat; Architecture, colonial; Casbah; Forts and fortifications; Indigenous peoples; Morocco, Description and travel; Panoramic views; Religious buildings; Street scenes
  - Subseries 2. People
    - Sultan and Moroccan peoplen.d., 14 postcards (Box 2, Folder 22)
      14 postcards of Moroccan people and leaders. 5 show images of the Sultan, his family, or his ministersSultan's sons on pilgrimage to Moulay-Idriss; Sultan in Tangiers; Arrival of Mouley Arafa, Sultan's uncle, receiving William II in Tangiers; Sultan visiting the Agricultural Exposition; Manebhi, Minister of War; 9 depict images of Moroccans, including grain merchants, camps of nomads, children, a marabout in the oasis, street scenes, military camp
      CAP; Edicion Boix Hermanos, Melilia; Edition Hell, Tangiers; Editions d'Art Felix, Marrakech; Gevaert L.L.; Maillet, Casablanca; Photo Flandrin; Children, Indigenous eoples; Merchants; Military facilities; Morocco, Description and travel; Parades and processions; Sultans
- Series 19. Oceania
  - Oceanian.d., 12 postcards (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Cunge, photo.; Edition Boiset Edition Phos, Pointe-a-Pitre, Guadaloupe; H. Bauwens, editeur, Ghent; Helio Braun, Paris; Laboratoires La Biomarine, Dieppe; Pacific Cable Office, Suva, Fiji; Photo Etienne Coussinier; Architecture, colonial; Fiji; Guadaloupe; Harbors; Indigenous peoples; Martinique; Missionaries; Noumea; New Caledonia; Oceans; Panoramic views; Papua
- Series 20. Senegal
  - Subseries 1. Cities
    - Subsubseries 1. Dakar
      - Dakarn.d., 50 postcards (Box 2, Folder 24)
        50 postcards, including many duplicates, of Dakar, Senegal. Images include: panoramic views of the city, the Court; Boulevard National; Place Protet; the Town Hall; the Town Hall gardens; the Government building (Palais du Gouvernement); Anse Bernard.
        Collection Generale Fortier, Dakar; Collection Nouvelle, Mme Bouchut, editeur; Edition A. Albaret, Dakar; Edition Joseph Helou, Dakar; Edition Quatineau; H. Grimaud & V. Lembert, Dakar; J. Benyoumoff et Ch. Djian; Architecture, colonial; Colonial power; Panoramic views; Senegal, Description and travel
      - Dakarn.d., 64 postcards (Box 2, Folder 25)
        64 postcards of Dakar, Senegal. Images include: Hotel de la Marine; Post Office, TSF; Monument Blanchet; Round-about between the Ecole and the Avenue Pasteur; Tourist office; Medical school; Government buildings; Museum of French West Africa; Train station; marketplace; the Port and the Palais du Port; Senegalese fishermen and boats; Casernes des Madeleines; Bay of the Madeleines; military camps
        Collection Generale Fortier, Dakar; Collection Gautron; Collection Nouvelle, Mme Bouchut, editeur; Edit. Antoine Challah, Dakar; Edit. Joseph Helou, Dakar; Edit. Maurice Viale; Edition Moreau, Dakar; Editions Carnaud Freres, Dakar; J. Benyoumoff et Ch. Djian; M.D. photo, Dakar; Robel, Dakar; Architecture, colonial; Colonial power; Fishing; Harbors; Markets; Military facilities; Monuments; Panoramic views; Post offices; Senegal, Description and travel; Train stations
      - Dakarn.d., 39 postcards (Box 2, Folder 26)
        39 postcards of Dakar, Senegal, mostly street scenes. Many duplicates. Images include: the Mosque; the Church; the Public Garden; Place Protet; rue des Essarts; Boulevard National; rue Parent; General Secretary; Boulevard Pinet-Laprade; Boulevard Maritime; Avenue Roume; rue Raffenel; rue de Thies; rue Vincens.
        Collection Gautron; Collection generale Dantan; Collection generale Fortier; Collection J. Benyoumoff; Collection Nouvelle, Mme Bouchut, editeur; Editions A. Albaret, Dakar; Edit. Maurice Viale; N.D. photo; V. Roche, Dakar; Architecture, colonial; Colonial Power; Gardens; Mosques; Parades and processions; Religious buildings; Senegal, Description and travel; Street scenes
      - Dakarn.d., 23 postcards (Box 2, Folder 27)
        23 postcards of Dakar, Senegal, and its environs. Images include: the indigenous village,;families and children; the oasis and garden of Hann; another (?) oasis near Dakar; and Cap Manuel.
        A. Albaret, Dakar; Collection Gautron; Collection generale Fortier, Dakar; Collection J. Benyoumoff; Collection Nouvelle, Mme Bouchut, editeur; Edition Maurice Viale; Children; Indigenous peoples; Oases; Religious education; Senegal, Description and travel; Street scenes; Villages
    - Subsubseries 2. Cities Except Dakar
      - Rochers de Billy; Ile de Goree; Kayes; Makana; Ngazobit; Rufisque; Saint-Louisn.d., 33 postcards (Box 2, Folder 28)
        33 postcards of towns and rural areas in Senegal. Images include the following: Rochers de Billy, Haut-Senegal; Ile de Goree: various views; Place principale; Place du Gouvernement; la Terrasse. Many duplicates. Kayes: Hotel du Gouvernement; Makana: road outside town; Ngazobit: cliffs nearby; Rufisque: panoramic views; indigenous village; Maisons Soucail and L. Vezia & Co.; Compagnie Francaise de l'Afrique Occidentale; covered peanut storage; Shipping of grain; radio antenna; Saint-Louis: panoramic view; caravan; quarter of fishermen; Avenue Dodds; Allee des cocotiers
        Collection Barthes et Lesieur; Collection generale Fortier; Collection Tennequin; Edit. A. Albaret, Dakar; Edition de l'Ecole Apostolique Lierre, Belgium; Edit. Diloutremer, Paris; Messageries Maritimes; Robett, edit., Rufisque; Agriculture; Architecture, colonial; Caravans; Cliffs; Colonial power; Fishing; Harbors; Indigenous peoples; Panoramic views; Senegal, Description and travel; Street scenes; Villages
  - Subseries 2. People and Scenes
    - People and scenesn.d., 33 postcards (Box 2, Folder 29)
      33 postcards of people, villages, and landscape in Senegal. The first two postcards are notable for the poems written on them by a French man to a woman in France. Others include images of the following subjects: girls spinning cotton; groups of boys, women, children; women drawing water from well; mission school; fighters; village scenes; mosque; fishing boats on river and fishernen's houses; caravan carrying salt; harvest of palm wine; oases
      Collection Albaret, Dakar; Collection generale Fortier; Collection Ideale; Collection "Le Bon Marche", Dakar; Edit. Joseph Helou, Dakar; H. Danel, Kayes; Helio De Graeve, Ghent; Boats; Caravans; Children; Fishing; Indigenous peoples; Mosques; Oases; Palm trees; Rivers; Senegal, Description and travel; Villages
- Series 21. Sierra Leone
  - Subseries 1. Freetown
    - Freetownn.d., 25 postcards (Box 3, Folder 1)
      25 postcards of Freetown, Sierra Leone, and its environs. Images include the following: Views of Freetown; Victoria Park; Custom's Offices; Tower Hill barracks; Commissariat; Wilberforce Station; Wilberforce Street; Westmoreland street; Susan's Bay (also known as Sawpit Bay); wharf and harbor; Leicester Hill; Waterfalls; villages; a woman "making Furrah"
      A. Lisk-Carew Photo., Freetown; Collection L.S.; F.M. Wolff, Hamburg; H. Thies, Hamburg; Architecture, colonial; Bays; Gardens; Harbors; Military facilities; Panoramic views; Sierra Leone, Description and travel; Street scenes; Waterfalls
  - Subseries 2. Towns Except Freetown
    - Boulam; Charlotte Falls; Congo Town; Hammock River Bridge; Songo; Waterloo; York Islandn.d., 12 postcards (Box 3, Folder 2)
      12 postcards of villages and rural areas in Sierra Leone, excluding Freetown. Images are as follows: Boulam: village scenes; Charlotte Falls; Congo Town: two views near Congo Town; Hammock River Bridge: the bridge; Songo Town; Waterloo: village scene; York Island: view of village and persons, two postcards of river scenes
      A. Lisk-Carew, Photo., Freetown; H. Thies, Hamburg; Bridges; Panoramic views; Rivers; Sierra Leone, Description and travel; Villages; Waterfalls
- Series 22. Soudan, French
  - French Soudan/Malin.d., 10 postcards (Box 3, Folder 3)
    10 postcards of the former French military territory of Soudan, present-day Mali and part of Mauritania. Images include the following towns and sites: Bamako: Monument to tirailleurs soudanais, Djenne: village, boat; Koulikoro: military post, Tahoua: military post, tribal chiefs; Tomboctou: mosque, view; views by bodies of water
    Edition S.E.A.; Lauroy, editeur; Archaeological sites; Indigenous peoples; Mali; Military facilities; Monuments; Mosques; Rivers; Soudan, French; Villages
- Series 23. South Africa
  - Subseries 1. Cities
    - Subsubseries 1. Cape Town
      - Cape Townn.d., 13 postcards (Box 3, Folder 4)
        13 postcards depicting Cape Town, South Africa. Images include the following: views of city with Table Mountain in background; Devil's Peak; Lion's Head; Grand Parade and City Hall; Houses of Parliament; Castle; St. George's Cathedral; harbor; Van Riebeeck statue; Adderly Street; Standard Bank
        C.N.A., Ltd.; John G. Vain, Cape Town; Kimble Productions; The Newman Art Publishing Co., Cape Town; The Valentine & Sons Publishing Co., Cape Town; Architecture, colonial; Harbors; Panoramic views; Religious buildings; South Africa; Street
    - Subsubseries 2. Cities Except Cape Town
      - Bloemfontein; Durban; Johannesburg; Rondebosch; Valley of a Thousand Hills; Victoria Fallsn.d., 17 postcards (Box 3, Folder 5)
        17 postcards of towns and sites in South Africa. Of special note: a series of "ricksha boys" in Durban. Images on these postcards include the following subjects: Bloemfontein: Railway station, Durban: Post office; Town Hall; Ricksha boys (6 postcards); Johannesburg: King George's Street; gold mines; art gallery; Rondesbosch: rural estate, Valley of a Thousand Hills, Natal: 2 views, Victoria Falls: 2 views of bridge
        A. R., Durban; C. Borckenhagen & Co.; G.S.J., Durban; John G. Vain, Cape Town; The Newman Art Publishing Co., Cape Town; The Recordia Photo and Gramophone Co, Johannesburg; Smart & Copley, Bulawato; The Valentine & Sons Publishing Co., Cape Town; Bridges; Colonial power; Post offices; Railway stations; South Africa; Street scenes; Tourist attractions; Waterfalls
  - Subseries 2. People and Wildlife
    - People and wildlifen.d., 19 postcards (Box 3, Folder 6)